Guide to the Juan E. Méndez Papers, 1980-2017 and undated RL.11330
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- UN Special Rapporteur on Torture, 1992-2017
  - Engagements/Events, 2010-2017; 7
    - American University International Law Symposium, 2012 (Box 8)
      Material related to symposium, including handwritten notes, program, and event schedule.
    - American Academy of Forensic Science Workshop, 2011 (Box 8)
      Includes workshop packet, presentation and speech by Méndez, and material by other presenters.
    - IRCT Meeting, 2011 (Box 8)
      Includes program for International Rehabilitation Council for Torture Victims (IRCT), meeting schedule, and packets on preventing torture.
    - Implementation of Mandela Rules - Brazil, 2016 (Box 8)
      Includes travel information, handwritten notes, correspondence related to travel, packets and information regarding the Nelson Mandela Rules for the Treatment of Prisoners, and schedule of events.
    - Torture of Juveniles Expert Consultation, 2014 (Box 8)
      Includes schedule of events, news releases, U.N. reports, research, presentation draft, and email correspondence.
    - Pakistan Police Torture Webinar, 2014 (Box 8)
      Includes notes on webinar and material package for participants.
    - Torture in Health Care Experts Meeting, 2012 (Box 8)
      Includes packets on "When Treatment is Torture: A New Approach to Protecting People with Disabilities Against Improper Medical of Psychiatric Treatment," email correspondence, UN Reports on medical treatment of intersex people, drug treatment, event schedule of meeting, and travel materials.
    - Torture in Health Care Experts Meeting, 2011; 2 folders (Box 8)
      Includes pamphlets, programs, meeting notes, schedule of events, presentations, and research material on the relationship between medicine and torture.
    - Geneva Meeting, 2011 (Box 10)
      APT Global Forum on the OPCAT Keynote Speech by Juan E. Méndez.
    - Engaging with UN Special Procedures to Advance U.S. Social Justice Conference, 2016; 44 files; approximately 155 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Document files in PDF.
    - Events, 2010-2015; 9 files; approximately 821 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Document files in DOC and PDF.
    - IASP, 2014-2017; 2441 files; approximately 627 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in JS, XML, HTML, CSS, MSG, JSON, PHP, and SVG formats. Image and graphic files in GIF, PNG, JPEG, VML, EXIF, and THMX formats. Document files in plain text, PDF, PDF/X, PPT, and DOC formats. Compressed files in ZIP, GZIP, and RAR formats.
    - London Visit Amnesty International, 2011; 32 files, 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Document files in PDF and DOC. Web files in XML, THMX, and HTML. Graphic file in VML.
  - Country Files, 2005-2017; 8
    - Ambassador Porter and Panama, 2015 (Box 8)
      Report on denial of medical treatment to Ambassador Arthur Porter who is being held in detention in Panama.
    - Argentina Cases, 2010-2016 (Box 9)
      Reports on torture and mistreatment of prisoners in Argentina.
    - Australia, 2015 (Box 9)
      Questions for Méndez
    - Bahrain, 2009-2014; 2 folders (Box 9)
      Reports, handwritten notes, travel documents, drafts, and email correspondence regarding various visits to Bahrain.
    - Brazil, 2010-2015; 5 folders (Box 9)
      Reports on torture and prison conditions, handwritten notes, email correspondence, and other material from various visits to Brazil by Méndez.
    - Brazil, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Canadian Class Action Cases, 2013-2017 (Box 9)
      Materials related to case against solitary confinement in Canadian prisons, includes legal briefs, research materials, and appendices containing information about to solitary confinement.
    - Chile: Regional consultation, 2011 Jun. 15-17 (Box 3)
      Speech, notes, schedule
    - China, 2014-2015 (Box 3)
    - Colombia: Visit to Colombia, 2015 Apr. (Box 3)
    - Confronting Crimes Against Humanity in Mexico, 2016 (Box 9)
      Talking points on systematic torture and crimes against humanity in Mexico for an Open Society Foundation event.
    - Côte d'Ivorie, 2011 (Box 9)
      Letter from Méndez to ambassador of the Ivory Coast regarding treatment of M. Masile Mahan Gahé.
    - Egypt, undated (Box 9)
      Handwritten notes related to Mohammed Sultan, a prisoner on a hunger strike in Egypt.
    - Ethiopia and Yemen, 2015 (Box 9)
      Advance and unedited versions of the mistreatment of Andargachew Tsege, a British national arrested in Yemen and imprisoned and tortured in Ethiopia.
    - Georgia, 2015; 3 folders (Box 9)
      Materials from 2015 visit to Georgia including handwritten notes, travel material, reports in English and Georgian, and reports on detention, torture, and prisoner treatment.
    - Ghana, 2013-2014; 2 folders (Box 9)
      Reports, handwritten notes, email correspondence, and other material from the U.N. regarding torture and poor treatment of workers and prisoners in Ghana.
    - Indonesia, 2010-2016; 2 folders (Box 9)
      Material from visit to Indonesia including handwritten notes, U.N. reports, and pamphlets from Human Rights Watch and other human rights organizations.
    - Iran: Truth commission, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Kyrgyzstan, 2010-2011; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Mauritania, 2016; 2 folders (Box 9)
      Material from visit to Mauritania including handwritten notes, reports filed by U.N., material in Arabic, and travel materials.
    - Mexico: Mission to Mexico, 2014 Apr. 21-May 2; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Mexico, 2015-2017; 2 folders (Box 9)
      Materials related to visits to Mexico, includdes travel arrangements, event schedules, handwritten notes, reports, emails, and formal recommendations from the U.N. on torture in Mexico.
    - Morocco, 2010-2012; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Observations of the Committee Against Torture - Chile, 2009 (Box 8)
      Reports in Spanish.
    - Philippines and Balochistan, 2009-2011 (Box 8)
    - Reports on Torture in U.S. Prisons, 2011-2012; 2 folders (Box 8)
      Reports, pamphlets, and information packets on torture and inhuman treatement in the United States prison system.
    - Russia: healthcare/drugs, undated (Box 3)
    - Sikhs in India, 2016 (Box 8)
    - Spain, 2010 (Box 9)
      U.N. report on human rights in Spain.
    - Sri Lanka, 2010-2016; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Tajikistan, 2012 (Box 8)
    - Tajikistan: Report from visit, 2014 (Box 3)
    - Tunisia: Mission report draft, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Tunisia, 2011 (Box 9)
      Material from mission to Tunisia, includes handwritten notebooks, travel arrangements, event schedule, reports on Tunisia's treatment of prisoners and torture.
    - United Kingdom: Commission of Inquiry and visit to London with Amnesty International, 2011 Feb. (Box 3)
    - United States: general, 2005-2014 (Box 3)
    - United States: Guantanamo Bay, Bradley Manning case, 2011 (Box 3)
      Visits, correspondence, statements
    - United States: Prisoner letters to Mendez, 2014 (Box 3)
    - Uruguay, 2010-2014; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Venezuela, 2007-2016; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Country Files, 2010-2012; 10 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Document files in DOC and PDF. Compressed files in ZIP format.
  - Office/Administration, 2005-2017; 9
    - Human Rights Council: Manfred Nowak reports, 2010 (Box 3)
    - Special Rapporteurs annual meetings, New York, 2011 Jun. (Box 3)
    - UN General Assembly meetings, New York, 2011, 2014; 2 folders (Box 3)
      Draft statements, agendas, talking points
    - UN SRT meetings, Geneva, 2010-2014; 4 folders (Box 3)
      Notes, schedules, talking points
    - Comision Interameriana de Derechos Humanos (CIDH) meetings, 2011; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - General Information on OHCHR, 2005 (Box 6)
      Mission statement and other information related to the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR)
    - U.N. Human Rights Council Reports, 2010 (Box 6)
      Reports presented to the Human Rights Council
    - Job Listings, 2009 (Box 6)
      Job description and request for applications for assisstant to Special Rapporteur on Torture.
    - U.N. Office of Drugs and Crime, 2017 (Box 6)
      Program from expert group meeting in Vienna, 2017.
    - General Material, 2008-2010 (Box 6)
      Guidelines, training manuals, facts and figures, information sheets, and other material related to the office of the Special Rapporteur on Torture.
    - Notice of Appointment and Job Information, 2010-2012 (Box 6)
      Notices of appointment, certificates of achievement, codes of contact, rules, and other administrative information.
    - Text of Convention Against Torture, undated (Box 6)
      Official Text of U.N. Convention Against Torture
    - Human Rights Council Reports, 2011-2012 (Box 6)
      HRC Reports including reports on torture
    - HRC Observation Report, 2012 (Box 6)
      Report of the Special Rapporteur on torture and other cruel, inhuman or degrading treatement or punishment and addendum.
    - Amnesty International Letters, 2010 (Box 6)
      Letters from Manfred Nowak on behalf of Amnesty International regarding torture and ill-treatment for nations, including China, Equatorial Guinea, Oman, Nigeria, Moldova, Eritrea, Indonesia, and Kazakhstan.
    - Activities, 2010-2017; 397 files; approximately 51 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in MSG, JS, CSS, HTML, XML, THNX, JSON, AXD, and PHP. Document files in DOC, PDF, plain text, XLS, and PPT. Graphics files in GIF, PNG, and JPEG.
    - UN Human Rights Council Report, 2010-2012; 10 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Document files in DOC, DOCM, and RTF.
    - UN Docs, 2009-2017; 920 files; approximately 62 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in XML, THMX, HTML, JS, WEBARCHIVE, and CSS. Graphics files in GIF, VML, PNG, and JPEG. Document files in DOC, PDF, and plain text.
  - Subjects/Research, 1992-2017; 10
    - Death penalty, 2012 (Box 3)
      Notes, UN mandate
    - Forensics, 2004-2014 (Box 3)
    - "Pro-Bono Project for the UN SRT" Thematic report: The Use of Forensic Science to Document and Prevent Torture, 2014 (Box 3)
    - NGOs, 2010-2014 (Box 3)
      Notes, handouts
    - Solitary confinement, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Solitary confinement (USA), 2010-2014 (Box 3)
    - Heartland Alliance, 2011 (Box 6)
      Heartland Alliance correspondence and information
    - Aero Contractors, 2011; 4 folders (Box 6)
      Correspondence and research material related to Aero Contractors, an aviation firm headquartered in Johnson County, NC which participated in the extraordinary rendition of terrorist suspects abraod.
    - Solitary Confinement, 2012 (Box 6)
      Report: "Solitary Confinement and its Human Rights Implications"
    - Solitary Confinement, 2016; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Notes, report from Weill Gotshal and Manges LLP
    - Aaron Isby Case, 2006 (Box 6)
      Aaron Isby letter to Méndez
    - Solitary Confinement, 2012-2017; 7 folders (Box 6)
      Includes material on solitary confinement in California, ACLU briefing papers, TAMMS C-Max, Viktor Bout, and IACHR hearing.
    - Prison rape elimination, 2009 (Box 6)
      Material and reports on efforts to end prison rape
    - Ojore N. Lutalo, 2010 (Box 6)
      Material related to imprisonment of Ojore N. Lutalo
    - Mumia Abu-Jamal, 1997 (Box 6)
      Material related to the imprisonment of Mumia Abu-Jamal
    - Maryland Legal Aid, 2012 (Box 6)
      Research material related to Maryland Foster Care system and use of pscyhotropic drugs on foster children.
    - Extraordinary Rendition, 2012-2014 (Box 6)
      Material related to processes and inquiries of extraordinary rendition by the United States and torture in Guantanamo Bay.
    - Universal Rights Group, 2016 (Box 6)
      Correspondence and information about the Universal Rights Group based in Switzerland.
    - Columbia Law School Human Rights Initiative, 2015 (Box 6)
      Columbia Law School Human Rights Insitute guide and program information.
    - NGOs, undated (Box 6)
      Information and assorted NGO material
    - Rhonda Pence, 2013 (Box 6)
      Account of meeting with Rhonda Pence an activist concerned about microwaves being used for mind control purposes.
    - Amnesty International Reports on Extraordinary Rendition, 2010 (Box 6)
      Reports by Amnesty International on Extraordinary Rendition in Europe.
    - Comisión Interamericana de Derecho Humanos, 2017 (Box 6)
      Strategic Plans, work agendas, and other documents from the CIDH.
    - Gendered Perspectives on Torture, 2011-2015 (Box 6)
      Notes, research material, and drafts of reports and research papers on gendered perspectives on torture.
    - Protocols of Interrogation, undated (Box 6)
      Includes two packets entitled "Protocols of Interrogation" and "Publication on Children Deprived of Liberty" which includes annotations.
    - Florence ADX, undated (Box 6)
      Research materials and correspondence regarding the the United States Penitentiary Administrative Maximum Facility (ADX) in Florence, Colorado.
    - A Sourcebook on Solitary Confinement, 2008 (Box 6)
      Photocopy of sourcebook by Sharon Shalev.
    - United States v. Henry Michael Houston, 2007 (Box 6)
      Photocopies of photographs of conditions in the Florence ADX prison.
    - Standard Minimum Rules for Treatment of Prisoners, 2012 (Box 6)
      Email correspondence and drafts related to Standard Minimum Rules (SMR) for the treatment of prisoners as defined by the U.N. COmmission on Crime Prevention and Criminal Justice.
    - Tribute to Nigel Rodey, 2017 (Box 6)
      Tribute to Professor Sir Nigel Rodey by Juan Méndez.
    - ICJ Global Redress and Accountability Initiative, 2017 (Box 6)
      Bulletin and emails relate to a project designed to combat impunity and promote redress for gross human rights violations.
    - Misc. Pamphlets/Programs, 2011-2017 (Box 6)
      Various pamphlets and programs from events and meetings held during the time period listed.
    - Syed Hashmi, undated (Box 10)
      Handwritten letter from prisoner named Syed Hashmi about his experience in Florence ADX.
    - Solitary Confinement Prisoner Spreadsheet, undated (Box 10)
      Spreadhseet with information about California prisoners who are in solitary confinement.
    - Newspaper clippings and articles, 1992-2015 (Oversize-folder 1)
      Various newspapers, news clippings, and articles (some laminated) on a variety of subjects related to solitary confinement, human rights abuses, and cases related to torture.
    - Universal Jurisdiction, 2009-2012; 229 files; approximately 38 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in JS, HTML, XML, CSS, PHP, WEBARCHIVE, MSG, and ASP. Document files in plain text, PDF, and DOC. Graphics and image files in GIF, JPEG, and PNG.
    - Extraterritorial application, 2015-2017; 7 files; approximately 116 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in MSG, HTML, CSS, and XML.
    - Torture, 2010-2017; 28373 files; approximately 7 gigabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
      Web files in JS, MSG, HTML, XML, CSS, THMX, JSON, PHP, WEBARCHIVE, ASP, JSP, and AXD. Graphics, audiovisual, and image files in JPEG, GIF, PNG, VML, SVG, FLV, TIFF, 3GPP, MPEG, APNG, and BMP. Document files in plain text, DOC, PDF, PDF/X XLS, RTF, XLM, PPT, and WEBP. Compressed files in EXIF, ZIP, and RAR.
- International Center for Transitional Justice, 2004-2011
  - Correspondence (general), 2006-2011 (Box 4)
  - Transitional Justice research, resources, and events, 2009 and undated (Box 4)
  - "Prosecution of Crimes Committed in U.S. Counter-Terrorism Policy and Operations", 2009 (Box 4)
    Policy brief draft, notes
  - Board of Directors Executive Committee meetings, 2008-2009 (Box 4)
  - ICTJ organization/leadership, 2007-2008 (Box 4)
  - Staff phone and address lists, undated (Box 4)
  - Peru: Independent Oversight/institutional reform visit by Mendez, 2004 Jun. (Box 4)
  - Prevention of Genocide conference, Berne, 2008 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Trip to Netherlands and Stockholm, 2009 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Trip to Helsinki and Geneva, 2009 Mar. (Box 4)
  - Skoll Award for Social Entrepreneurship, Skoll World Forum, 2009 Mar. (Box 4)
  - Consultative Conference on International Criminal Justice, Harvard Law School, 2009 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Thomas Lubanga OSJI/IWPR conference, 2009 (Box 4)
    Notes and statements about Lubanga Trial
  - "Transitional Justice in Development," Berlin, 2010 Jan. (Box 4)
  - Administrative, 2009; 10 files; approximately 189 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Includes HTML web files as well as plain text, Microsoft Word and Microsoft Excel document files.
- Writings, 1980-2015 and undated
  - Mendez's biography, C.V., undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous and undated notes by Mendez (Box 5)
    From ICTJ, UN, and other positions, engagements, and meetings.
  - "Accountability for Past Abuses," Human Rights Quarterly, 1997 (Box 5)
    Photocopy and article
  - Amici Curiae: International Jurists in Support of Affirmance, Sosa vs. Alvarez-Machain, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Autobiography, 2009 and undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    Correspondence, drafts, outlines
  - "The Death Penalty and the Absolute Prohibition of Torture and Cruel, Inhuman, and Degrading Treatment or Punishment," Human Rights Brief, 2012 (Box 5)
  - El desafio de la prevencion del genocidio, undated (Box 5)
    Draft
  - "Employer Sanctions and Other Labor Market Restrictions on Alien Employment: The 'Scorched Earth' Approach to Immigration Control," NC Journal of International Law, 1980 (Box 5)
    Offprint
  - Evolving Standards for Torture in International Law, 2015; 4 files, approximately 315 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Includes document files in DOC/DOCX.
  - "Human Rights Policy in the Age of Terrorism," St. Louis University Law Journal, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "I Used to be Innocent: Readings in the Study of Torture" prologue draft, 2006 (Box 5)
  - Justicia Transicionial: Manual Para America Latina, 2011 (Box 5)
    2 versions: Portuguese and Spanish
  - "Lo que ensena la experiencia," chapter in Victimas sin Mordaza, undated (Box 5)
    Photocopy
  - "Patrones que Configuran Actos de Genocidio Conforme a la Jurisprudencia Internacional", 2012 (Box 5)
  - publications, 2010-2015; 792 files, approximately 148 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Includes documents in PDF, Microsoft Word DOC, and Plain text. Image files in PNG, JPEG, and GIF formats. Web file formats in XML, HTML, JSON, JS, and CSS.
  - "Reconciliacion Nacional, Justicia Transnacional, y el Tribual Penal Internacional," Anuario, 2002 (Box 5)
  - "Remarks on Intervention," Case Western Reserve Journal of International Law, 2008 (Box 5)
  - "Some Patterns of Violation of the Independence of Judges and Lawyers," American Society of International Law, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Taking a Stand The Evolution of Human Rights, 2010-2011; 934 files; approximately 75 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC, PDF, DOCM, plain text, and XLS. Graphics and image files in VML, JPEG, and GIF. Web files in XML, HTML, and MSG.
  - Terrorism and International Law, 2010; 10 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in DOC. Compressed files in ZIP.
  - "Torture in Latin America", undated (Box 5)
    Photocopy of chapter
  - Publisher correspondence, releases, etc., 2006-2011 (Box 5)
    Regarding various works.
  - Writings by Others, 1995-2011; 22 files; approximately 17 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF, DOC, and RTF.
- Lectures, Teaching, Consultancies, Leadership Roles, 1995-2017
  - Speaking engagements (general), 2000s (Box 5)
  - "Comparative Analysis of International and National Tribunals," 5th Annual Ernst C. Steifel Symposium, 1995 (Box 5)
    Transcript printed in New York Law School journal
  - Comision Interameriana de Derechos Humanos (CIDH) presidency, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
  - Oxford University Advocacy course, 2004 (Box 5)
    Notes, program
  - Oxford University Master's in International Human Rights Law course, 2008 (Box 5)
  - "Foro Regional Sobre Prevencion de Genocidio," Buenos Aires conference, 2008 Dec. (Box 5)
  - Forum 2000 Conference, Prague, 2009 May (Box 5)
  - Humanity United consultation on international justice, San Francisco, 2009 Jul. (Box 5)
  - "Primer Foro Nacional Sobre Libertad de Expresion y Prensa: Jurisprudencia y Estandares Internacionales," Mexico, 2009 Aug. (Box 5)
  - Ford Foundation consultant, Peace and Social Justice Program, 2009 (Box 5)
    Contract
  - "Enhancing Cooperation between Regional and International Mechanisms for the Promotion and Protection of Human Rights," OHCHR-OAS regional consultations, 2009 (Box 5)
  - Manhattan Committee on Foreign Relations, 2009 (Box 5)
  - International Bar Association Human Rights Institute co-chair, 2009-2010 (Box 5)
  - Human Rights consultation, MacArthur Foundation, 2010 Feb. (Box 5)
  - Human Rights Program: Open Society Justice Initiative, Harvard Law School, 2010 May (Box 5)
  - Marek Nowicki lectures, Budapest and Warsaw, 2010 Nov. 6-11 (Box 5)
  - International Criminal Court (ICC) conferences and meetings, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Crimes Against Humanity project, Washington University in St. Louis, 2011 Sept. (Box 5)
  - "Jornadas para corresponsales extranjeros y periodistas," Buenos Aires panels, 2011 Nov. (Box 5)
  - "National Security and Human Rights" expert meeting for the National Security and Human Rights Campaign, Open Society Foundation, 2013 Jan. (Box 5)
  - Task Force on Detainee Treatment, The Constitution Project, 2013? (Box 5)
    Meeting binder
  - ISISC: "Meeting of Experts on the Establishing of Principles and Best Practices for International and National Commissions of Inquiry," Italy, 2013 Mar. (Box 5)
  - FIBGAR: Congreso Jurisdiccion Universal, Madrid, 2014 May (Box 5)
  - Ill Antonio Cassese lecture, Florence, 2014 Nov. (Box 5)
  - Advisory Board Genocide Intervention Network, 2010; 3 files; 218 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
  - Agenda da Diversidade, 2013; 14 files; approximately 3 gigabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Informational videos on diversity from Brazil.
    Audiovisual files in VOB, BOP, and IFO.
  - AIUSA, 2010; 1 file; approximately 1 kilobytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document file in plain text.
  - American Bar Association, 2009-2015; 53 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, MSG, and HTML. Image and graphics files in VML, JPEG, and GIF. Document files in PDF and DOC.
  - American Society of International Law, 2010-2014; 104 files; approximately 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in XML, THMX, JS, MSG, HTML, WEBARCHIVE, and CSS. Graphics and image files in VML, GIF, and PNG. Document files in PDF and plain text.
  - APT, 2012; 15 files; approximately 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Web files in MSG. Document files in PDF and DOC.
  - Argentina, 2009-2017; 15400 files; approximately 625 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in plain text, PDF, DOC, XLS, PPT, and RTF. Graphics and image files in GIF, PNG, JPEG, SVP, and VML. Web files JS, CSS, PHP, WEBARCHIVE, MSG, XML, HTML, THMX, and WEBP.
  - Auschwitz Institute, 2017; 3 files; approximately 4 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF. Web file in MSG.
  - AUWCL Proposal and Documents for Oak, 2011-2017; 13 files; approximately 34 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11330-SET-0001)
    Document files in PDF and XLS.